Isaac Destura

Email: <u>isaacdestura@gmail.com</u> Phone Number: +63 917 771 4128 Linkedin: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/isaac-destura</u> Github: <u>https://github.com/nimitz-Bear</u>

Website: https://isaacdestura.dev/

I'm a Computer Science student at the University of Nottingham, graduating in 2024. I'm most familiar with OOP languages, especially Java (> 5 years) and C (>2 years).

I'm comfortable using MacOS, Linux and version control systems like Git. I also have experience with agile methods, like Kanban and Scrum. I enjoy learning and want to apply what I've learned so far in a role as a software engineer.

Skills

Languages: Java, C, C++, Dart, HTML, CSS, JS, Python Frameworks/Databases: Firebase, SQL, Flutter and Bootstrap

Education

University of Nottingham

September 2021 - Present Predicted Grade: Class 1

BSC Computer Science (Hons)

- Modules include Programming and Algorithms (97), C++ (93), Group Project (82), etc

Brent International School Manila

August 2016 - May 2021

- IB HLs in Computer Science (7), Business (6), and English (5)
- IB SLs in Mathematics AA (7), Chinese (6), and History (5)

Relevant Experience

What3Words Dialler - Project Manager

September 2022 - May 2023

- Led a University group project, producing an Android calling app for a client at ATOS
- Responsible for managing a team of 7 other developers
- Involved skills like Java, agile, testing and project management.

HackSoc, Speaker Acquisition Secretary

May 2023 - Present

- Communicate with industry professionals, professors and other students to organize computer science-related talks for HackSoc.
- Organize speaker events and hackathons like <u>HackNotts</u>

Computer Science Mentor

July 2022 - Present

- Responsible for mentoring new first year students
- Run workshops on topics like Git, Linux and C

Projects

- To learn Dart, I worked on a <u>to-do/reminders app</u> implemented using Firebase. This project uses Github actions as a form of CI/CD.
- Implemented a <u>Discord Bot</u> using Python, SQL and external APIs, that allows users in the same server to share their locations with each other on an interactive map.
- Created a 2D Roguelike game for my C++ module featuring procedural generation, leading to a 93% mark in the module
- Software development in Java using MVC and some other OOP design patterns